Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Collection, Part II: Field Recordings AIA.031.002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series I: Digitized Tapes, 1965-1997
  - I:A Reference CDs of Digitized Tapes
    - Private Performances, 1970-1992, circa 1970-Jan 27, 1992
      - Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (mandolin and guitar) and Mulvihill’s students. Interview and private performance recorded in the Bronx, NY. Mulvihill’s students discuss their interest and involvement with Irish music interspersed with eight minutes of traditional music performed by Mulvihill and Moloney. Students interviewed are: Carmel Glendon, Elizabeth Moran, Maureen Roche, Bernadette Lucy, Eileen Ivers, Michael Carolan, Patricia Conway, Dawn Mulvihill, Margie Mulvihill, Theresa Fitzpatrick, Philip Lane, Maureen O’Hara and Seamus Burke. (One CD – Length: 00:57:34) aiamm12R, Apr 30, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Mulvihill, Martin, Band Practice. Bronx, NY. Rehearsal of traditional music recorded in the Bronx, NY. (One CD – Length: 00:30:10) aiamm158, Feb 17, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Mulvihill, Martin, Ceili Bands (folder one). Recording session in Connecticut for the Green Linnet recording, Irish Music, the Living Tradition (1009). The Glinside, Eire-Og and Glincastle Ceili Bands. Eileen Ivers (fiddle), Patricia Conway (accordion), Pat Burke (accordion) Gail Mulvihill (banjo), Martin Mulvihill (fiddle) Mick Moloney (guitar) and Unidentified (piano) play solos, duets and trios. (Four CDs – Total length: 02:11:58) aiamm322R, 323R, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Mulvihill, Martin, Ceili Bands (folder two). Recording session in Connecticut for the Green Linnet recording, Irish Music, the Living Tradition (1009). Eileen Ivers (fiddle), Gail Mulvihill (banjo), Martin Mulvihill (fiddle) Mick Moloney (guitar) play in various combinations. (One CD – Length: 00:46:55) aiamm324R, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Mulvihill’s, Martin, School of Irish Music, Bronx, NY. Private performance of traditional music recorded in the Bronx, NY. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:56:25) aiamm159C, Feb 19, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano, b. 1915, Chicago, IL, d. 1993) Recording session in Chicago, IL. Innovative for her melody playing on the piano, Kane is joined by Johnny McGreevy (fiddle) for a few selections. (One CD – Length: 00:20:58) aiamm143R, May 2, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Recording session in Chicago, IL. (Four CDs – Total length: 01:43:15) aiamm145R, 146R, 147R, 148R, May 3, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Recording session in Chicago, IL. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:50:53) aiamm149R, 150R, May 5, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Interview. Kane discusses the tunes she recorded on May 5, 1980 in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:03:17) aiamm150R (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) Recording session in Chicago, IL. Kane is joined by Johnny McGreevy (fiddle) for several selections. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:27:38) aiamm62R, 63R, 64R, Aug 15, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano) and Unidentified Musicians. A compilation of recordings of traditional music. The original tape belonged to fiddler and composer Ed Reavy. (Two CDs – Total length: 02:12:28) aiamm27R, Oct, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) Recording session in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:25:40) aiamm144R, May 2, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) Interview in Chicago, IL. Kane and McGreevy discuss the tunes they recorded on Aug 15, 1982. (One CD – Length: 00:05:02) aiamm64R (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle), Carroll, Liz (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:06:50) aiamm144R, May 2, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Neary, Eleanor Kane (piano), Moloney, Mick (mandolin) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:05:43) aiamm150R, May 5, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Nelson, Barry (folder one) (vocals, guitar, mandolin, whistle, b. May, 1944, Belfast, Co. Antrim) Interview recorded at McGurk’s Irish Pub, St. Louis, MO. Nelson discusses his personal and musical history. (Four CDs – Total length: 02:05:11) aiamm231C, 232C, Jun 19, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Nelson, Barry (folder two) (vocals, guitar, mandolin, whistle, b. May, 1944, Belfast, Co. Antrim) Interview recorded at McGurk’s Irish Pub, St. Louis, MO. Nelson discusses the Irish bar circuit in the U.S. (One CD – Length: 00:32:05) aiamm233C, Jun 19, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - O’Brien, Andy (guitar and vocals, b. Co. Kerry), McComiskey, Billy (accordion, b. Brooklyn, NY) Interview in New Canaan, CT. Members of The Irish Tradition, O’Brien and McComiskey discuss their personal and musical histories and selections they recorded for the 1978 Green Linnet LP, The Corner House. (One CD – Length: 00:15:10) aiamm142R, Jul 29, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - O’Brien, Paddy (accordion, b. 1945, Daingean, Co. Offaly), Flynn, Mike (vocals, b. Co. Clare), Moloney, Mick (banjo). Private performance of traditional music recorded in Philadelphia, PA. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:28:15) aiamm235C, May 23, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes, whistle) Interview recorded in New York, NY. Piper, organizer and teacher Ochs discusses his personal and musical history. Topics include: non-Irish playing Irish music, piping, the Irish Arts Center. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:44:38) aiamm237, 238, Feb 24, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes, whistle) Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length:00:27:53) aiamm250, Apr 3, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes, whistle) Recording session and interview in Philadelphia, PA. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:19:34) aiamm251, Apr 4, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Ochs, Bill (uilleann pipes, whistle) Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. (Four CDs – Total length: 00:55:31) aiamm246, 247, 248, 249, Apr 17, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle, b. 1932, Co. Derry), Moloney, Mick (guitar). Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length: 00:14:01) aiamm319R, Feb 8, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar). Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. for the 1991 release, The Music of Ed Reavy. (One CD – Length: 00:05:56) aiamm320R, May 24, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar). Recording session in [Philadelphia, PA] for the 1978 Green Linnet release, Slow Airs and Set Dances. (One CD – Length: 00:28:51) aiamm325R, Feb 11, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar). Recording session in [Philadelphia, PA] for the 1978 Green Linnet release, Slow Airs and Set Dances. (One CD – Length: 00:26:26) aiamm327R, Mar 26, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (mandolin, guitar) Private performance of traditional music recorded in [Philadelphia, PA?] (One CD – Length: 00:08:54) aiamm218C, Jun 10, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Philadelphia, PA (One CD – Length: 00:09:47) aiamm220C, Jan 31, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Private performance in Philadelphia, PA. O’Donnell plays his own compositions. (One CD – Length: 00:05:07) aiamm316C, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music, including original compositions, recorded in Philadelphia, PA (One CD – Length: 00:16:06) aiamm317C, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Posen, I. Sheldon (guitar, vocals, folklorist), Moloney, Mick (mandolin, vocals) Private performance of traditional songs recorded in Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length: 00:15:42) aiamm181C, Mar 28, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Purcell, Al (uilleann pipes, whistle, b. May 17, 1929, Dublin, d. Sept 28, 2000, Detroit, MI.) Interview and recording session in Detroit, MI. A student of piper Leo Rowsome, Purcell discusses his personal and musical history, tunes he recorded for Mick Moloney, and Irish music in Detroit. He performs traditional music solo and in duet with his student, Terry McKinney. (Three CDs – Total length: 00:47:22) aiamm32R, 33R, Mar 5, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Purcell, Al (uilleann pipes), McKinney, Terry (whistle, b. Toronto, ON.), Unidentified (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Detroit, MI. (One CD – Length: 00:21:27) aiamm112R, Mar 5, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Quinn, Louis (fiddle, b. 1904, Newtonhamilton, Co. Armagh, d. March, 1991) Interview in Flushing, Queens, NY. Co-founder of the Traditional Irish Musicians Association, Quinn discusses his personal and musical history. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:43:25) aiamm48R, 49R, May 17, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Quinn, Louis (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Recording session in Flushing, Queens, NY for the release, The Music of Ed Reavy. (One CD – Length: 00:19:41) aiamm50R, May 17, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Rafferty, Mike (flute, b. 1926, Larraga, Ballinakill, Co. Galway), Moloney, Mick (long necked mandolin). Recording session in Rafferty’s home, New Jersey. (One CD – Length: 00:13:27) aiamm328R, Jan 23, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Rafferty, Mike (flute, uilleann pipes), Wynne, Peter (fiddle). Private performance of traditional music and interview recorded by Peter Wynne. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:27:59) aiamm329R, Nov, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Reavy, Ed (fiddle, b. 1897, Barnagrove, Co. Cavan, d. 1988) Interview in Philadelphia, PA. Composer and fiddler Reavy discusses his compositions and the process of composition interspersed with reminiscences and personal history. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:04:39) aiamm152C, Oct 23, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Reavy, Ed (fiddle) Interview recorded in Philadelphia, PA. Composer and fiddler Reavy discusses Irish music in Philadelphia from the 1920s to the 1970s. (One CD – Length: 00:31:53) aiamm133R, May 24, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Reavy, Ed (fiddle), Reavy, Joe (fiddle, b. 1927, Philadelphia, PA.), Bonner, Kathy (piano) Recording session in Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length: 00:22:10) aiamm122R, Jul 21, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Regan, Will (radio host) Interview recorded in [Philadelphia, PA.]. Host of Philadelphia’s Will Regan Irish Hour, a Saturday show on WVCH-AM, Regan discusses his show, broadcasting and concert promotion in Philadelphia. Part two of an interview. Part one is missing. (One CD – Length: 00:27:53) aiamm273C, Jan 27, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Reynolds, Paddy (fiddle, b. Dec 17, 1920, Dromard, Co. Longford, d. Jun 15, 2005, New York) Private performance of traditional music interspersed with chat recorded in NY. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:50:41) aiamm51R, 52R, Jan 30, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Rice, Noel (flute, b. 1936, Geashill, Co. Offaly) Interview in Chicago, IL. Musician and teacher Rice discusses his personal and musical history and Irish culture and music in Chicago. (One CD – Length: 00:27:22) aiamm1R, May 5, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Rice, Noel (flute) Recording session and interview in Chicago, IL. Rice discusses the tunes he recorded and some of his musical influences after a recording session. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:17:48) aiamm55R, Mar 5, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Roche, Pat (dancer, b. Mar 24, 1905, Carrigaholt, Co. Clare, d. Oct 24, 2004) Interview in Philadelphia, PA. Organizer of Chicago’s first feis, dancer and dance teacher Roche discusses his personal and dance history. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:50:34) aiamm1R, May 9, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Shannon, Joe (uilleann pipes, b. 1920, Co. Mayo, d. Dec 26, 2004), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Chicago, IL. (One CD – Length: 00:33:14) aiamm154C, Dec 13, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Shannon, Joe (uilleann pipes), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) Interview in Chicago, IL. National Heritage Fellowship recipient Shannon and influential fiddler McGreevy discuss their personal and musical histories and tunes they recorded for Mick Moloney. (One CD – Length: 00:37:02) aiamm129R, May 6, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Shannon, Joe (uilleann pipes), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) Interview in Chicago, IL. National Heritage Fellowship recipient Shannon and influential fiddler McGreevy discuss tunes they recorded for Mick Moloney. (One CD – Length: 00:37:02) aiamm33R, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Shannon, Joe (uilleann pipes), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) (folder one) Recording session in Chicago, IL. Mick Moloney (banjo) plays on several tunes. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:15:18) aiamm87R, 88R, 89R, Mar 5, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Shannon, Joe (uilleann pipes), McGreevy, Johnny (fiddle) (folder two) Recording session in Chicago, IL. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:59:16) aiamm90R, 91R, Mar 5, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - St. Paul Musicians: Gans, Jamie (fiddle), Bob [?], Sam [?]. Recording session and interview in St. Paul, MN with members of The Plough and the Stars Ceili Band. Discussion includes learning traditional Irish music and its sustenance in St. Paul. (Three CDs: Total length: 00:56:23) aiamm177R, 178R, Mar 6, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Teahan, Terry “Cuz” (melodeon and concertina, b.1905, Glauntane, Co. Kerry) Interview and private performance. Traditional music interspersed with anecdotes by Teahan, a student of fiddler Padraig O’Keefe, recorded in Chicago. (Four CDs – Total length: 02:17:02) aiamm 59R, 60R, 61R, 140R, Jul 28, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Thornton, Frank (flute, b. Moyvane, Co. Kerry) Interview in Chicago, IL. Co-founder of the Irish Musicians Association of America, Thornton discusses his personal and musical history and the development of the IMAA. (One CD – Length: 45:30) aiamm1R, May 6, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Tunney, Paddy (sean nos singer, b. Jan 28, 1921, Glasgow, d. Dec. 6, 2002) (folder one) Recording session in Philadelphia for the 1982 Green Linnet release, The Stone Fiddle. (Four CDs – Total length: 00:56:38) aiamm171R, 172R, 173R, 174R, Apr 24, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Tunney, Paddy (sean nos singer) (folder two) Recording session and interview in Philadelphia for the 1982 Green Linnet release, The Stone Fiddle. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:40:01) aiamm175R, 176R, Apr 24, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Ui Cearuil, Treasa (sean nos singer, b. mid 1950s, Carna, Connemara, Co. Galway) Recording session and interview. Sean nos singer, Ui Cearuil sang and recorded with Cherish the Ladies. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:20:41) aiamm257, Aug 12, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Public Performances, 1965-1997, Jun 25, 1965-Feb 22, 1997
      - Session in New York. Musicians include: Jack Coen, Mike Preston (flutes), Johnny Cronin, Denis Murphy (fiddles), Paddy Murphy, J. McAuliffe, John McMahon. Recorded by Ed Reavy. (One CD: Length: 01:00:31) aiamm13R, Jun 25, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Session in New York. Musicians include: Jack Coen (flute), Andy McGann, Larry Redican, Jim Curran (fiddles), Gerry Lynch, Gerry McCarthy (accordions), Michael Redican (mouth organ). Recorded in New York City by Ciaran MacMathuna. (One CD: Length: 00:16:55) aiamm139R, Pre-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Redican, Larry (fiddle, b. 1908, Dublin, d. 1975, Mineola, NY), Unidentified (piano). Recorded at a ceili in the Irish Center (Commodore Barry Club), Philadelphia, PA by Ciaran MacMathuna. Also a short interview in Irish with two women, Nora Ni Fhearraig, from Gort an Choirce and Brid Ni Thuil, from Falcarragh and a short interview about the Commodore Barry Club with another woman, Nancy McCahill, in English. (One CD – Length: 00:17:02) aiamm139R, Pre-1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Irish Arts Center. Informal concert performance at the Irish Arts center, New York, NY. Musicians include: Bill Ochs (pipes, whistle), Margaret Barry (banjo, vocals) (One CD – Length: 00:47:24) aiamm255, Jul 16, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Mick Moloney. (guitar, banjo, vocals) Solo concert performance by Mick Moloney. (One CD - Length 00:20:19) aiamm321R, circa 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle, b. Co. Derry), Moloney, Mick (guitar, banjo, mandolin and vocals). Concert performance in Boston, MA. (One CD – Length 00:42:33) aiamm153C, Jan 11, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Vesey Trio, John. Radio broadcast on WXPN-FM, Philadelphia, PA. created by Thomas Standeven. Musicians: John Vesey (fiddle, b. 1924, Ballincurry, Co. Sligo, d. 1995), Thomas Standeven (uilleann pipes), Canice Fahey (flute/vocals) with Chris Delaney (fiddle). (One CD – Length: 00:29:18) aiamm336R, Apr 28, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Vesey Trio, John. Radio broadcast on WXPN-FM, Philadelphia, PA. created by Thomas Standeven. Musicians: John Vesey (fiddle), Canice Fahey (flute/vocals), Thomas Standeven (uilleann pipes, vocals), and Pupils: Lois Cooter (flute), Rick Moreau (uilleann pipes), Keri Jost (uilleann pipes, whistle), Owen Ballard (uilleann pipes, whistle), (Two CDs – Total length: 00:47:48) aiamm337R, 339R, May 12, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Vesey Trio, John. Created for radio broadcast on WXPN-FM, Philadelphia, PA. by Thomas Standeven. Musicians: John Vesey (fiddle), Thomas Standeven (uilleann pipes), Canice Fahey (flute/vocals). (One CD – Length: 00:31:30) aiamm338R, Jun 9, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Chieftains: Sean Keane (fiddle), Martin Fay (fiddle), Sean Potts (whistle), Michael Tubridy (flute), Paddy Moloney (uilleann pipes), Derek Bell (harp), Peadar Mercier (bodhran). Concert performance at the Irish Center (Commodore Barry Club), Philadelphia during their first USA tour. (Two CDs – Total length 01:30:13) aiamm162C, Nov 22, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Concert and Session at Lenape Park, Philadelphia, PA. Musicians include: Mike Preston, Mike Rafferty (flutes), Mick Moloney (banjo), Thomas Standeven (uilleann pipes), John Vesey (fiddle), Gena Dunlop (vocals, bodhran), Joe Mulroney (vocals), Maureen McDade Irish Dancers, Randy Moore (vocals, guitar, banjo), Unidentified Bluegrass and Old Time musicians. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:50:37) aiamm198C, 199C, Aug 6, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Session at the Bunratty, Bronx, NY. Musicians include: Paddy Reynolds (fiddle), Mick Moloney (banjo). (One CD – Length: 00:18:36) aiamm151R, Jan 2, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Session at Jack Coen’s, Bronx, NY. Musicians: Jack Coen, Mike Preston, Mike Rafferty (flutes), Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina, whistle), Kathleen Coen, Ann McIlvaney (piano). (Two CDs – Total length: 01:03:51) aiamm93R, 94R, Feb 8, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Session at the Bunratty, Bronx, NY. Musicians include: Paddy Reynolds, Andy McGann, Johnny Cronin (fiddles), Mick Moloney (guitar, banjo, vocals), Patty Moriarty (accordion). (One CD – Length: 01:01:56) aiamm228C, Feb 21, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Session at the Breffni Inn (Irish Traditional Musicians Association: John Glynn Branch), Queens, NY. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:20:07) aiamm76R, 77R, 78R, Feb 22, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Session at the Bunratty, Bronx, NY. Musicians: Paddy Reynolds, Andy McGann, Pat Keogh (fiddles), Mick Moloney (banjo, guitar, vocals), John Nolan, Patty Moriarty (accordions), Paul Winchell, Gerry Mahoney (vocals). (Two CDs – Total length: 01:00:03) aiamm155C, Feb 30, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Session at Jack Coen’s, Bronx, NY. Musicians: Johnny Cronin, Paul Ryan, Miles Krassen (fiddles), Jack Coen, Mike Flynn, Mike Preston (flutes), Sean McGlynn (accordion), Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina), Eileen Clohessy (whistle), Mick Moloney (banjo), Maureen Glynn, Kathleen Coen (piano), Maureen Doherty (flute, whistle and accordion). (Three CDs – Total length: 01:13:13) aiamm56R, 57R, 58R, Mar 7, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Session at Jack Coen’s, Bronx, NY. Musicians: Jack Coen, Mike Flynn (flutes), Joe Madden, Sean McGlynn (accordions), Johnny Cronin (fiddle), Maureen Glynn (piano). (One CD – Length: 00:32:41) aiamm92R, Mar 7, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Session in Chicago. Musicians include: Johnny McGreevy (fiddle), Joe Shannon (pipes), Larry (L.E.) McCullough (whistle). (One CD – Length: 00:40:00) aiamm14R, Mar 24, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Session at Jack Coen’s, Bronx, NY. (folder one) Musicians: Mike Rafferty, Jack Coen, Mike Flynn (flutes), Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina, flute), Sean McGlynn (accordion), Mick Moloney (guitar, mandolin, banjo). (Three CDs – Total length: 01:32:40) aiamm67R, 68R, 69R, May 9, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Session at Jack Coen’s, Bronx, NY. (folder two) Musicians: Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina, flute), Mike Rafferty, Jack Coen, Mike Flynn (flutes), Sean McGlynn (accordion), Mick Moloney (guitar, banjo). (Two CDs – Total length: 00:35:13) aiamm70R, 71R, May 9, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Session in Washington, D.C. Musicians: Mick Moloney (banjo), Johnny McGreevy (fiddle), Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina), Sean McGlynn (accordion), Michael Flatley (flute), Russell Crehan. (One CD – Length: 00:58:25) aiamm157C, Jul 12, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Session with Martin Mulvihill, Bronx, NY. Musicians include: Martin Mulvihill (fiddle), Gus Collins (flute), Gail Mulvihill (banjo), Mick Moloney (banjo). (One CD – Length: 00:32:20) aiamm158C, Feb 17, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Session at the Bunratty, Bronx, NY. Musicians: Johnny Cronin (fiddle), Mick Moloney (banjo). (One CD – Length: 00:15:24) aiamm134R, Feb 18, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Session in Germantown, Philadelphia, PA. (at Mick Moloney’s home) Musicians include: Joe McKenna (uilleann pipes), Eddie Cahill (flute), Tim Britton (uilleann pipes, flute, tin whistle), Mick Moloney (banjo), Mike Stoner (bodhran). Four CDs – Total length: 02:08:48) aiamm213C, 214C Additional unidentified accordion, fiddle and guitar at the end of tape aiamm214C., May 15, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - McKenna, Joe (pipes, whistle), McKenna, Antoinette (harp, vocals), Moloney, Mick (banjo). Radio broadcast. Traditional music and interview recorded at WXPN, Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length: 00:26:08) aiamm263, Jun 16, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - O’Donnell, Eugene (fiddle) and Moloney, Mick (banjo, guitar, vocals), Unidentified (dancers) Concert performance in Philadelphia, PA. (One CD – Length: 00:13:16) aiamm216C, Sep 17, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Across the Western Ocean – The Story of Irish Traditional Music in America. (folder one) National Public Radio series written, hosted and produced by Mick Moloney. Episodes include: “The Star of Kilkenny” and “The Sidewalks of New York.” (Four CDs – Total length: 03:58:32) aiamm285C, 286C, 287R, 288C, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Across the Western Ocean – The Story of Irish Traditional Music in America. (folder two) National Public Radio series written, hosted and produced by Mick Moloney. Episodes: “Twixt a Tear and a Smile,” “The Quay of Philadelphia,” “Ed Reavy’s Fancy,” “Once Around the Country.” (Four CDs – Total length: 03:58:11) aiamm289C, 290C, 291C, 292C, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Across the Western Ocean – The Story of Irish Traditional Music in America. (folder three) National Public Radio series written, hosted and produced by Mick Moloney. Episodes: “Chief O’Neill’s Favorite,” “The Banks of the Charles,” “Flowers of Spring.” (Four CDs – Total length: 03:04:28) aiamm293C, 294C, 295C, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)